mychoicedegree.com 2016-03-31

# My Choice Degree

## MyChoiceDegree.com Web Privacy Statement

MyChoiceDegree is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our Websites, so we want you to know what information we collect when you visit one of our sites, how we use that information, and how you can update it. We reserve the right to append or otherwise modify this Privacy Statement at any time, so please re-visit this page occasionally to check for updates. **Information We Collect**  
We collect various types of information from our visitors so we can adjust our site to meet our users' needs and expectations. Some of this information is collected automatically through cookies and other information is collected when you register for any of our online services or when you request information from one of our partners. **Information Collected Automatically**  
The types of information your browser or Internet session automatically sends us each time you visit one of our sites, which we automatically collect, includes:

  * Your browser.
  * Your computer's operating system.
  * Your navigation path, i.e., the URLs of where you come to our site from, which of our pages you visit, and where you go as you leave.
  * Your IP address.

This and other information lets us see how users are finding our sites, and it tells us which pages are visited the most often so we can make our Websites more useful. **Information You Provide to Us**  
In addition to the information automatically collected by your browser, we also collect information that you provide to us when you request information about a particular school or educational program. Our websites provide users the opportunity to request information from schools, and to learn about various education opportunities. These information request sites require users to provide us with contact information (name, address, phone number, email address, gender, age, work experience, etc.) as well as information about their interest in one of our educational partners (universities, colleges, test prep companies, etc.) We collect this information that you provide, and may use it to make your future requests from our websites easier by pre-populating contact forms with the information that you have provided. We provide this contact information that you provide to the educational partner that you requested information from. Customer interest information is collected to determine what information the customer wishes to be sent. **How We Use This Information**  
We use the information we automatically collect to help us better plan our Website to meet your Internet needs. Information you provide to us is used for marketing purposes, and may result in follow-up communications. In addition, from time to time, we may share personally identifiable information (such as e-mail addresses) about our customer base with carefully selected third parties, so they can offer goods and services that we believe may be of interest to our customers. All third parties are bound by the federal CAN-SPAM Act and required to follow all consumer opt out rules and regulations. **Your Rights Our Obligations**  
The company respects the privacy of users visiting our sites and will abide by all applicable laws concerning the release of personal information. On an occasion we may use certain directory information that we have collected to send you information about products and services, or updates and other information we think may be of interest to you. We may share this information with our educational partners to bring similar information to your attention. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes. Please contact us to request your name and address be removed from our lists. If you do not want to receive our e-mail marketing, please submit a request to have your e-mail address removed by emailing: unsubscribe@mychoicedegree.com. **Legal Protections and Law Enforcement**  
We may disclose information about our users, including your personal information, in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process or other valid law enforcement measures; to comply with a legal obligation; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Sites and applicable laws; or to protect the legal rights, interests, or safety of the Sites, our users or others. We may also use device identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, internet service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you. **Our Security Measures**  
Our Websites have reasonable security measures in place to help protect personal information under our control. **Why We Use "Cookies"**  
When you visit some of our sites, we use cookies to keep track of your information. This small piece of program code resides on your computer and stores your contact information for all of our request information sites. We do this so you are not required to re-enter your contact information as you move from one site to another. In addition, some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by us and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. You can generally opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie. Look for the cookie options in your browser in the Options or Preferences menu. However, please be aware that some areas of the Sites may not provide you with an acceptable user experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. **Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. **Clear Gifs**  
We and our third party advertising companies may employ a software technology called clear gifs that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to discern the online movements of users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personally identifiable information. Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the Web site or advertising company would match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company or site. **Links From Our Site To Other Sites**  
Some of our sites may contain links to other sites external to our sites. When you access these external Websites, the providers of the sites will have access to certain information about you. MyChoiceDegree is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any Websites which we do not directly control. **Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, or other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

## Definitions

**Cookies**  
Data created by a Web server that is stored on a user's computer. It provides a way for the Website to keep track of a user's patterns and preferences and, with the cooperation of the Web browser, to store them on the user's own hard disk. The cookies contain a range of URLs (Web addresses) for which they are valid. When the browser encounters those URLs again, it sends those specific cookies to the Web server. For example, if a user's ID were stored as a cookie, it would save that person from typing in the same information all over again when accessing that service for the second and subsequent time during the same browser session. You can opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie. Look for the cookie options in your browser in the Options or Preferences menu. **IP (Internet Protocol) Address**  
This is the address of a computer attached to a TCP/IP network. Every client and server station must have a unique IP address. Client workstations have either a permanent address or one that is dynamically assigned for each dial-up session. IP addresses are written as four sets of numbers separated by periods; for example, 204.171.64.2. **Browser Session**  
A browser session is defined as the period of time a browser is in consecutive use. The session begins when you open the browser and ends when you close it. When you reopen the browser, you begin a new session. **SSL Encryption (Secure Sockets Layer)**  
The leading security protocol on the Internet. When an SSL session is started, the browser sends its public key to the server so that the server can securely send a secret key to the browser. The browser and server exchange data via secret key encryption during that session. We also use SSL encryption whenever we display your personal information (e.g., name and address, scheduled courses, grades). **URL (Uniform Resource Locator)**  
An Internet address. URLs are used to locate sites on the Internet and to navigate between sites and pages within sites. The URL for MyChoiceDegree is www.mychoicedegree.com.
